I see...
Sasuke and Naruto are in
an alternate Time-Space
as well as Sakura and Kakashi.
Naruto and Sasuke are
the core participants in the battle.
(ヒルゼン)そうですか
別空間に ナルトと サスケ。
I wish we could have gotten
your advice and aid a bit earlier.
それに サクラとカカシも。
This lower body is a part of Madara
after he became the Ten Tails' Jinchuriki.
(ハゴロモ)ナルトと サスケが
主体となって戦っておる。
(扉間)助言をいただけるなら→
In short, it contains Ten Tails,
Madara and Hashirama...
もっと早くに
してほしかったですね。
No, rather Nine Tails, Madara
and Hashirama.
(ハゴロモ)この下半身は→
十尾の人柱力になったあとの
マダラの一部。
No, rather Nine Tails,
Indra and Ashura.
I'm only able to emerge like this now
because their chakra is finally one.
つまり 十尾と マダラと 柱間。
いや 九尾と マダラと 柱間。
Going back to the jutsu
you mentioned earlier,
いや 九尾と インドラと アシュラ。
just what exactly are you doing to do?
そのチャクラが 今 やっと揃い
わしが出てこられたのだ。
I will weave the signs for the jutsu.
But this jutsu requires
a vast amount of chakra...
(ミナト)…で あなたが先ほど
言われた術のことですが→
具体的には
どのようにするのですか？
which I don't have right now
since I've given it away.
術の印は わしがやる。
There's very little time.
I ask you to just do as I say.
ただ この術には
膨大なチャクラがいる。
わしには今
そのチャクラがない。
渡してしまった。
あまり時間もない
わしの言うとおりにしてくれ。
aimaina hyouden koshiraete hitatteru no
I create a vague critical biography and wallow in it
seisei saisai nani o mada matteru no
Generation after generation, time after time,
what are you still waiting for
itsunomanika hitori ni natta
I was all alone before I knew it
tameiki hitotsu haite nageite
Breathed out a single sigh and lamented
jounetsu moyashita ano koro o
Those days of burning passion
shinketsu sosoide torimodosunda
Put your heart and soul into getting them back
en de tsunagareba kono hibi mo
Bind these days with bonds and perhaps
suteru hodo koware tenaidarou
They can be salvaged
ayumi o tomenaide
Don't stop walking forward
kibou o sutenaide
Don't give up hope
douka furimuite
Please look back
dou ka kimiyo
Please, if you would
jin jin kokoro ga itamunara
If the heart throbs with pain
kannen no ori o uchiyaburu nda
Break through the ideology that imprisons you
enen tsukihi wa megurukedo
Time goes around for eternity
suteru ni wa yami ga asaidarou
But the darkness within you is still shallow,
not worth throwing it all away
jounetsu moyashita ano koro o
Those days of burning passion
shinketsu sosoide torimodosu nda
Put your heart and soul into getting them back
ai o wakeaeba kono hibi mo
If we love each other then surely these days will
mouichido kimi o terasudarou
Once again, shine upon you
The Two of Them...
Always
This man lent me his power.
That's how we were able to get here.
He did?
(サクラ)この人が
力を貸してくれたの。
だから たどり着けた。
Oh no...
(サスケ)こいつが？
Damn it... I can't...
Not until I can bring them back...
(オビト)うう！
いけない！
Hang on!
《クソ こいつらを
連れ帰るまでは…》
Will I...
break my promise again?
しっかり！
《俺はまた 約束を
守ることができないのか？
Rin?
リン…》
You know, Rin, you saving me,
is really the same as you
saving the world.
((リンが 俺を
救ってくれるってことは つまり。
Hmm?
I mean...
It's because I'm gonna become
the Hokage and end this war!
それは世界を救うってことと
同じなんだよな。
(リン)え？
だって ほら。
For me to do that I have to
stay strong and healthy in this world.
俺は火影になって
この戦争を終わらせるわけだろ。
So... how do I put it?
それには 俺が
この世に元気でいないと。
If you don't stay close
and keep an eye on me...
それにはやっぱ
なんて言うの？
I mean...
俺のこと ずっと
側で見ておいてくれないと。
Well...
つまり その…。
Y-You got so close all of a sudden!
Don't scare me like that!
うわ！
え？
You just said to stay close
and keep an eye on you?
だ だって いきなり
近すぎるからさ！
びっくりしちまうだろ！
側で見ておいてくれって
言ったでしょ ウフフ。
Yeah, I did.
So watch over me.
I'm going to wear the Uchiha crest...
and definitely become the Hokage!
ああ 言ったさ
見ててくれ。
俺は うちはの紋章を背負って
必ず火影になるんだ！
Okay!
Oh man, oh man, oh man!
This is the one day I can't be late!
うん！
NINJA ACADEMY
ENTRANCE CEREMONY
《やべえ やべえ やべえ！
今日だけは
遅刻するわけにはいかねえんだ》
- Where do you wanna go?
- I don't know, where should we go?
頑張るぞ！
これから楽しみだよね。
It's the entrance ceremony
and you're already late.
どこ行く どこ行く？
Someone like you has no business
being in the Academy.
はあ。
(カカシ)入学式から遅刻か。
む！
You'll never make it.
It's okay.
そんなやつに
アカデミーに入る資格はない。
I got this just for you.
無理だな。
(リン)大丈夫よ。
For me?
Yes! Just submit this
and you'll be able to enroll.
これ ちゃんと
もらっておいたから。
Thank you! You're a lifesaver!
お 俺の？
(リン)ええ。
この書類を出せば
問題なく入学できるって。
Keep pampering him and
he'll never be cured of his tardiness.
Shut up! Do you wanna fight?
助かった 恩に着るぜ！
Begin!
(カカシ)甘やかしてっと
こいつの遅刻癖なおんねえぞ。
(オビト)うるせえ！ やるか この！
始め！
Stop right there!
そこまで！
That's amazing!
うわ～！
かっこいい！
What's with that headband?
You passed!
Congratulations!
Thanks.
お前 その額あては…。
合格したのね おめでとう。
あぁ。
Aren't you going to congratulate me?
As if! I'll catch up to you in no time!
なんだ 祝ってくれないのか。
Just you wait!
誰が！
すぐに追いついてやるからな。
Obito...
覚えてろ！
オビト…。
Class is starting. Let's go.
Rin...
授業が始まるよ 行こう。
Keep...
Keep watching over me, okay?
リン。
Huh?
俺を… 俺を見ててくれよな。
I...
I'll catch up to him!
え？
Then I'll surpass him and
俺… あいつに追いつくから。
I'll become the Hokage,
no matter what!
そんで 追い抜いて→
必ず火影になるから！
Don't worry,
I'll always be watching.
うん。 大丈夫 ちゃんと見てるよ。
I found you, Obito!
Huh? Rin!
あっ 見つけた オビト！
あ？ リン！
Are you all right?!
うわっ。
あっ！
I just slipped.
I'm okay. I'm okay.
イテテ…。
大丈夫!?
Here is the graduation certificate
for Obito Uchiha!
ハハハ… ちょっと滑っちまった。
大丈夫 大丈夫。
This certifies that you have graduated
from the Hidden Leaf Ninja Academy.
卒業証書 うちはオビト。
You are commended for persevering
through the rain and wind
木ノ葉隠れ忍者アカデミーの
卒業を証する。
to reach this milestone!
それと 雨の日も風の日も→
Here! Congratulations on graduating.
よくここまで
修業と努力を続けました。
Rin!
はい 卒業おめでとう。
Thank you, Rin.
リン…。
No one's here to watch.
But this makes me happier than
receiving it from Grandpa Hokage!
ありがとう リン。
みんないねえけど→
火影のじいちゃんに渡されるより
ずっと嬉しいや。
We've been assigned
to a team and now...
this is our first step as shinobi!
配属も決まったし
忍としての第一歩だぜ。
I still have a long ways to go,
but I'm a little bit closer to
becoming the Hokage... right?
先はまだ長えけど→
ちょっとは
火影に近づけた… よな？
CHUNIN EXAMS
FIRST STAGE TEST
ヘヘッ。
I'M ALWAYS WATCHING YOU.
-RIN
CHUNIN EXAMS
THIRD STAGE
ONE-ON-ONE BATTLES
I'm going to have you pay me back
in full for the last time.
The "last time"?
Do your best, Obito!
この間のお返しは
たっぷりさせてもらうからな。
(ガイ)この間って…。
頑張って オビト！
All right... Just watch me!
Begin!
Wha—?!
よし 見ててくれ！
The winner is Might Guy!
始め！
え？
What is he doing?
ホァチャー！
ぐはっ！
勝者 マイト・ガイ！
なにやってんだか。
So this is where you are.
スー ハァー。
O-Oh, it's you, Rin.
こんなとこにいたんだ。
It's only natural that Kakashi passed.
うわっ。 な なんだ リンか。
But we can do it too.
I know we can!
カカシが受かるのは当然だけど
私たちもできるよ きっと。
Let's practice hard for next year!
But it's hard to get pumped up
after watching Kakashi...
来年の試験 頑張りましょう。
What are you saying?!
でもよ カカシ見てると
なんだか やる気が出なくて。
なに言ってるの！
You're going to be the Hokage,
aren't you?
I'm always watching you!
火影になるんでしょ？
Okay!
私が ちゃんと見てるから。
ああ！
NINJA ACADEMY
Obito...
I did it!
I'm a Chunin now!
オビト？
You're late again!
ニッ！
A lot happened on my way here
and I got lost...
やったぜ！ 俺も中忍だ！
How come every path you take
is a roundabout route?
(カカシ)またまた遅刻だよ お前は！
Just walk a straight line!
いや 途中いろいろあって
道に迷っちゃってさ。
They're not falling into line at all,
are they?
お前の歩く道は
いつも どんだけ➡
That's for sure.
But you know, Sensei...
曲がりくねってるってのよ
ほんと！
Let me handle this.
なかなか 足並みが揃わないね。
確かに。 でもね 先生。
I'll watch over the two
of them... always!
Let's go...
... you guys!
そこは私に任せて。
I was stubborn and never at ease.
私が２人をちゃんと。
(行くよ。 ２人とも！))
But you never failed to
come to my rescue.
(オビト)意地っ張りで そのくせ
小さなことで一喜一憂する俺を→
キミはいつでも助けてくれたのに…。
Since it's a dream,
everything is how you want it!
((ゼツ : 夢だから
なんだって思いどおり。
Even the dead can be alive again!
A world of only victors...
(ゼツ)死んだ人だって
生きてることにできる。
A world of only peace...
A world of only love...
I will create such a world.
(マダラ)勝者だけの世界
平和だけの世界→
愛だけの世界
それらだけの世界をつくる。
Rin... again...
I'll create a world where
we can be together again.
(リン… もう一度 もう一度
キミのいる世界をつくろう))
Thank goodness!
You came back!
There's still something I must do.
よかった。 戻ったんですね。
We're going back, you two.
うっ…。
まだ成すべきことがあるからな。
Hang on to me.
戻るぞ ２人とも。
All right!
俺の体に触れておけ。
はい。
There's no mistake.
Those things...
They cut down
the Shadow Clones earlier.
(ゼツ)やっぱり そうだよ。
《ナルト : あれは！ 前に
影分身が やられちまった…》
The Clones are desperately
protecting that one.
There's no mistake, Mother.
The one with the Truthseeker Orbs
behind him is the real one!
(ゼツ)分身が 必死で守ってる。
間違いないよ 母さん。
背中に 求道玉を持ってるのが
本体だ。
There's no end to them!
無限かよ！
Am I powerless to do
anything but watch?
Right now, even Sakura and Obito
are desperately...
《俺は ただ見ているだけで
何もできないのか？
I...
今頃 サクラもオビトも 必死で…。
I really couldn't do much
for you as your teacher.
俺は…。
Nor you, Obito and Rin...
お前たちの師として→
as your friend.
たいしたことは
してやれなかった。
I just put on airs
because I was an elite,
オビト… そして リン。
友としても 同じだ。
and kept making mistakes.
It's not over yet!
エリートぶって 口先だけの
失敗ばかりを繰り返してきた》
There's no way I'm gonna lose!
まだ まだ！
ぜってぇ～
負けるわけにはいかねえんだ！
What am I doing wallowing,
when Naruto's fighting so hard?
うぉ～っ！
That's why I'm never any good.
《カカシ : ナルトが頑張ってるときに
何を感傷に浸ってるんだ!?
There should be something
I can still do!
だから ダメなんだ。
今の俺でも
まだ やれることはあるはずだ》
Obito!
Impossible!
It's Sasuke!
オビト！
He's here!
バカな！ サスケだと!?
来た！
Now, there's nothing to worry about.
(カグヤ)これで もう心配いらぬ。
No way!
Naruto!
Why you!
まさか…。
ナルト！
He passed the Truthseeker Orbs
to a clone?
We fell for something so simple!
こ… こいつ！
Thank you, Sakura and Obito!
(ゼツ)分身に
求道玉を持たせてやがったのか！
What? You're okay?
こんな簡単なことに…。
You scared us there!
ありがとうな サクラちゃん！ オビト！
なに… 大丈夫だったの？
びっくりさせやがる！
Sasuke!
Did you thank
Sakura and Obito properly?
Focus on the enemy!
サスケ！ ちゃんと
サクラちゃんとオビトに 礼言ったか？
Well, Naruto was always
unexpectedly cunning.
敵に集中しろ。
Mother...
《まぁ ナルトは昔から
意外に賢いからな》
Since they've reunited,
we have no other choice.
We can't afford to be stingy
with our chakra.
母さん。
あいつらが
揃ったのならしかたない。
I know that.
もう チャクラを出し惜しみしている
場合じゃないよ。
わかっている。
うわっ。
My body feels so heavy.
This terrain...
is digging into my body!
《体が重い。
この地面 体がくい込む》
I can't levitate!
A heavy gravity plane this time!
Except...
これじゃ 浮けねえ。
She's affected too.
《今度は 超重力の空間。
だが… やつも同じように》
くっ。
Oh no!
Damn it! The Visual Prowess
in my left eye hasn't...
まずい。
Dodge it, Sasuke!
《クソッ まだ左目の瞳力が》
かわせ サスケ。
Is the heavy gravity distorting your aim?
I've now adjusted for it.
I won't miss with the next one.
重さで狙いが狂うかい？
I won't let you!
今ので調節した 次は当たる。
させるか！ うっ…。
There's something that I can still do.
《俺にも まだできることはある》
I can at least be a shield for them!
《２人の盾に
なることくらいなら》
– Let me make it in time!
間に合え。
– Rin!
Again, you...
(２人)リン。
Thank you, Rin.
Obito and I will be joining you soon.
《キミはまた…》
《ありがとう リン。
We can catch up then...
together, the three of us.
俺も オビトも
そろそろ そっちへ行くよ。
Rin...
また３人で ゆっくり話をしよう》
This time, when I get there...
Let's spend some alone time together,
just you and me.
《リン 今度はあの世で→
少し俺と
２人きりの時間を過ごそう》
Kakashi would just be in the way.
I'm gonna leave him here.
《カカシは邪魔だ。
ここに置いていくよ》
This is... Kamui!
Obito! You!
《これは 神威》
Kakashi... You stay here
a little while longer.
オビト お前！
カカシ お前は当分こっちにいろ。
Don't you rush to follow us!
すぐに来んじゃねえぞ。
boku ni wa wakaru nda uso o tsuite iru kimi ga
I can tell when you're lying
naite ii yo koko ni zutto irukara
It's okay to cry because I'll always be here
sekaijuu ni koborete iru hontou no ai no kimochi
Feelings of true love spills out throughout the world
sagashidashite miushinatte yoake ga kuru no matteru
We search for it but lose it, while waiting for daybreak
migi no hoshi ni wa boku no namae o tsukete
The star on the right will bear my name
kimi ga yonde okureyo
Will you call out to it?
hidari no hoshi ni wa kimi no namae ga ne
The star on the left will bear your name
niau yo zutto soba ni irukara
It's perfect, because we'll always be together
After fighting you,
I feel like I've woken up.
When I was a kid, I'd imagine myself
as the Hokage so often.
I think it's because
you brought back...
that indescribable feeling of
exhilaration and uncertainty.
Next time on Naruto Shippuden:
"You Better..."
Don't laugh at Obito!